Malcolm Crum

Programmer and problem solver

+1 8056170017 crummynz@gmail.com github.com/crummy malcolmcrum.com

I'm a software developer with three years experience delivering quality code and six years working on first class software in fast-paced Scrum teams. In my next role I'm looking to work on solving interesting problems for a customer-facing product in an environment that challenges me to continue to grow. I love to code and to mentor fellow colleagues, and I enjoy leading and learning in equal amounts.

I am a New Zealand citizen with international experience looking to make a home in Melbourne from January 2019.

Experience

TestObject / Sauce Labs

Software Developer - 2015 to present

Backend Java development on our PaaS. Deeply involved in all aspects of the development process, from devops to deploys. Developed new features to reliably interact with physical Android and iOS devices, as well as maintaining and refactoring old code. Projects included:

- Created end-to-end testing strategy from unit tests to release validation to production monitoring, **achieving a 10x increase** in platform reliability
- Integrated seamless HTTP proxy service for device testing, allowing customers to test apps and services that require private network communication
- Split monolith into independently deployable services for integration into multiple datacenters, **enabling global distribution** of real device cloud platform

Sonos, Inc

Software Test Engineer - 2012 to 2015

Lead tester in a mature, fast-paced Scrum team. Took pride in ensuring first class quality over all of Sonos' software controllers.

Led feature and regression testing on seven major software releases for desktop and mobile platforms, including wireless setup, parallel updates, and an HTML5 webview for music services. Implemented strengthened testing practices and created tools to assist testing and development. Performed manual tests, created and set up automation frameworks and wrote automated tests for desktop and mobile apps.

Technical Support - 2005 to 2011

Provided technical assistance for hardware, desktop software, apps, wired and wireless networks, and music services for customers. Introduced and led the documentation of support tools and created internal wiki, later specialised towards network troubleshooting and training. During this time I saw Sonos grow from 50 people to 700. This direct contact experience with the customer base was an unexpectedly valuable time in my programming career, giving me a strong sense of user needs and the importance of user experience when developing quality products.

Education

UC Santa Cruz - *Graduated 2012*Bachelor of Science, Computer Science
Nominated for 2011 Sammy Award for "Penguin Pull" project

Skills

- Capable and comfortable with Java, Kotlin, Docker
- Experience with C#, Python, Angular, React, Kubernetes
- Scrum Master certified
- A keen and dedicated learner